want to say happy happy Sabbath to
everyone.
>> Happy Sabbath.
>> It's always a blessing to be on his side
of the grave, ain't it?
>> No matter what you going through,
when you wake up and your eyes open
>> and you still have a mind to deal with
this God and his book,
>> it's always a blessing. Yes, sir.
>> Now, what we going to do is what we
always do each Sabbath. We're going to
open up the book of the law.
Exodus the 20th chapter.
You out there with your Bible, open it
up.
Exodus chapter 20 and
we going to start at verse one.
20 and verse one. Go ahead and read,
brother.
>> And God spake all these words, saying, I
am the Lord thy God, which have brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shalt have no
other gods before me. Thou shall make
not make unto thee any graven image, or
any likeness of anything that is in
heaven above, or that is in the earth
beneath, or that is in the water under
the earth. Thou shalt not bow down
thyelves to them, nor serve them. For I,
the Lord thy God, am a jealous God,
visiting the iniquity of the fathers
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation of them that hate me,
and showing mercy to thousands of them
that love me, and keep my commandments.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Thou shall not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain, for the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that taketh his name
in vain. Remember the Sabbath day to
keep it holy. Six days shalt thou labor
and do all thy work. But the seventh day
is the Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In
it thou shalt not do any work. Thou nor
thy son, nor thy daughter, thy man's
servant, nor thy maid servant, nor thy
cattle, nor thy stranger that is within
thy gates. For in six days the Lord made
heaven and earth, the sea, and all them
is, and rested the seventh day.
Wherefore the Lord blessed the Sabbath
day, and held it. Honor thy father and
thy mother, that thy days may be long
upon the land which the Lord thy God
giveth thee. Thou shalt not kill. Thou
shall not commit adultery. Thou shall
not steal. Thou shall not bear false
witness against thy neighbor. Thou shall
not coveret thy neighbor's house. Thou
shall not coveret thy neighbor's wife,
nor his man's servant, nor his maid
servant, nor his ox, nor his ass, nor
anything that is thy neighbor.
>> Yes, sir. We just read the covenant,
didn't we? Go to Ecclesiastes the 12th
chapter.
Ecclesiastes the 12th chapter and we're
going to pick it up at verse 13 and 14.
The Lord did this so Israel can be
reminded.
Serve me.
We'll pretty much touch on a little bit
of that in the lesson, but go ahead and
read 13. Let us hear the conclusion of
the whole matter. Fear God and keep his
commandments. For this is the whole duty
of man.
>> Yes, sir.
>> For God shall bring every work into
judgment with every secret thing,
whether it be good or whether it be
evil.
>> Whether it be good or whether it be
evil. Let's go to Revelations the 22nd
chapter.
Let's go see what Jesus got to say.
He said them ten commandments that you
just read,
I'm the judge you going to stand before.
Revelations 22, pick it up at verse
13.
I am Alpha and Omega, the beginning and
the end, the first and the last. Blessed
are they that do his commandments, that
they may have right to the tree of life,
and may enter in through the gates into
the city.
>> Yes. For without are dogs, and
sorcerers, and mongers, and
murderers, and idolattors, and whosoever
loveth and maketh a lie. Uhhuh. So now
we just read what the Lord just he
closed this thing off. He said, "Look,
if you're not keeping the commandments,
this is where you got this is what you
got to look forward to."
But the title of today's lesson is the
powers that be.
Have y'all heard I don't know if
everybody watch the news or keep in
touch with what's going on in the world.
Y'all heard about the teen teenager
takeover.
>> Y'all heard about that.
>> So you got it in Michigan.
You got it in Chicago. They saying they
going to do it. Start doing it state
by state. The cities that's very
important. They say they going to do
that.
They don't understand who they going up
against though.
Especially us.
It's mostly our people that's doing this
stuff. They rebellious because they
don't have no knowledge.
The Lord his people perish for what? A
lack of knowledge.
And we failed generations before us or
the ones to come. We as parents, we fail
them.
We have to we ain't have to teach our
children these things. If we don't,
then somebody else going to do it and
you don't want them to do it. Let's
start this in Daniel the fourth chapter.
Let's see what Israel did. They chose
the belt.
Our ancestors chose the belt. And they
could have made it easy for us. I ain't
going to lie.
They could have made it easy.
I ain't going to say it's hard to read
the Bible when you look at this stuff,
but you be like, man, what would it what
would it have been like if we didn't
have to go through these things?
But we already in it.
We got to make the best of it while we
here though.
The book of Daniel, the fourth chapter,
the teenage takeover. Let's just let's
let's observe some of these stuff.
The very last, well, I ain't gonna say
the last time, but the first time that I
did this lesson,
we was in a hotel and Anthony Brown that
Sabbath, Anthony Brown ended up getting
killed.
Y'all remember the boy in Ferguson,
right?
>> Yes.
>> Mike Brown. Who else say?
>> Anthony.
>> Mike Brown. So now Mike Brown got killed
and I'm looking at the
lesson and I say if that young man had
have been here learning
none of that stuff would have took
place.
But
it's an example for what we need to do
when we're dealing with these
authorities cuz nobody teach them none
of that stuff. You get people pulled
over, they arguing with the police. And
I'm like, man, I I used to be afraid
when I got pulled over.
And I didn't do no talking back. Yes,
sir. No, sir.
But I don't understand what got in them,
but the book going to show us what got
in them. Let's start at Daniel the 4th
chapter. Pick it up at verse one. Daniel
the 4th chapter, verse one. We're not
going to go all the way to the
beginning. We going to go to the
familiar part. 4 verse one. What it say,
brother?
>> Nebuchadnezzar is a king unto all
people, nations, and languages.
>> Wait a minute. He is a king unto how
many people?
>> All people.
>> All of them. The nations language. If
you speak, he your king. Read.
>> That dwell in all earth.
>> Yes.
>> Peace be multiplied unto you.
>> Uhhuh. Skip down to verse 17 and read
that.
This matter is by the decree of the
watchers and the demand by the word of
the holy ones. Uh
>> oh. Go ahead.
>> To the intent that the living may know
that the most high ruleth in the kingdom
of men.
>> So who is it that's ruling
Nebuchadnezzar?
>> The most high. He just said right. Read.
>> And giveth it to whomsoever he will.
>> Uh
>> oh. He giveth it to whomsoever he will.
Read.
>> And setth up over it the basis of men.
>> Not those who are familiar. He's at the
bases of men. Skip down to verse 28.
Verse 28. Let's see what it say now.
Read.
>> All this came upon the king Neb
Nebuchadnezzar.
At the end of 12 months, he walked in
the palace of the kingdom of Babylon.
The king spake and said, "Is not this
great Babylon that I have built for the
house of the kingdom by the might of my
power and for the honor of my majesty?"
>> Yes, sir. Go ahead. While the word was
in the king's mouth, there fell a voice
from heaven, saying, "Oh, King
Nebuchadnezzar, to thee it is spoken,
the kingdom is departed from thee."
>> Wait a minute. Now, he got his kingdom
departed from him. Why? Because he
started talking like it was him, but it
was God. Go ahead and read.
>> And they shall drive thee from men, and
thy dwelling shall be with the beast of
the field.
>> Yes, sir. They shall make thee to eat
grass as oxen, and seven times shall
pass over thee.
>> That's enough. Let's go over to Matthew
the 10th chapter, cuz we just wanted
that part where the Lord sat him down
for that. Let's go over to Matthew the
10th chapter.
Let's see what Jesus got to say.
He always talked through his apostles.
Matthew chapter 10, we're just going to
read one verse.
10 and verse 29.
Yeah, I can tell I need glasses. You
know why?
Cuz I used to write small enough to
where I can read it myself.
Now I'm like, is that a zero or a one,
man?
And I Yeah. And I keep trying to avoid
it. I don't want to go to the eye
doctor, but I'm going to have to break
down and do it.
Matthew 10 and verse 29. We're going to
read that 29th verse. Let's see what
Jesus got to say about his father.
Read 29, brother. What he say?
>> Are not two sparrows sold for a father.
>> Uh oh. He talking about some He talking
about the fouls. Go ahead and read.
>> And one of them shall not fall on the
ground without your father.
>> Wait a minute. So if one of them should
die, a bird, he said the father know
about it,
we know he's know about it. Why? Because
he gave him breath of life.
>> So when he withdraw, he know exactly
which one it was, exactly the family it
come from, the age, all the way down to
the sex of the bird, male or female.
Let's move forward. Let's go to
Leviticus the 18th chapter. So he said
the father know about this thing. So
when stuff going on, they very in tune.
They paying attention.
Leviticus the 18th chapter.
And I know when when what was it?
Thanksgiving come up. I used to see
everything on Facebook.
Man, I ain't I don't want to deal with
this because they these people been
dealing with uh
they didn't killed these people, took
their land.
You know how long that's been going on?
The Lord said he set down one and he
raised up another.
So guess what? The people that was in
this land, they was doing something foul
that the Lord had to remove them.
And we going to read how the Lord deal
with that. Leviticus 18, pick up at
verse one.
With knowledge, you you get to see these
things and then you get to watch what
you saying.
You get to be very careful as to what
comes out of your mouth. 18 to1. What
did it say, brother?
>> And the Lord spake unto Moses, saying,
>> "Yes, sir."
>> Speak unto the children of Israel.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And say unto them, I am the Lord your
God.
>> Yes, indeed. What else?
>> After the doings of the land of Egypt,
>> uh,
>> wherein ye dwelt, shall you not do, and
after the doings of the land of Canaan,
what I bring you, shall you not do,
neither shall you walk in their
ordinances.
>> That's right. Go ahead. You shall do my
judgments and keep my ordinances to walk
therein. I am the Lord your God.
>> So when they was in another land, what
do they have to do? Still keep his
commandments,
>> right?
>> We act like when we get in here, we
don't have to do none of this stuff,
>> right?
>> Don't work like that. Skip down to verse
22, brother. Verse 22. Let's see what he
going to say. Let's look at something
that he gonna point out over here. They
was doing this in the land, but let's
see what they do over here. Go ahead.
>> Thou shalt not lie with mankind as with
womankind.
>> Uhoh.
>> It is an abomination.
>> So you don't do what? You don't do this
behavior right here. This is what he's
saying. Go ahead.
>> Neither shalt thou lie with any beast to
defile thyself therewith.
>> Yes.
>> Neither shall any woman stand before a
beast to lie down. Thereto it is
confusion.
>> So this is what they were doing in the
land of Canaan. Defile not yourselves in
any of these things. For in all these
the nations are defiled, which I cast
out before you, and the land is defiled.
Therefore, I do visit the iniquity
thereof upon it, and the land itself
vomited out her inhabitants.
>> So, how did they leave? The Lord allowed
them. And he said, listen, your behavior
is what got you kicked up. Get kicked
out. Guess what's going to go on this
land pretty soon? The sin is going to
reach to the heavens and the Lord say
they out of there.
Then you have everybody go back to their
na their home state wherever you came
from.
Israel over there going back to
Jerusalem.
Wherever you at in the four corners of
the earth you going back to your natural
your natural land. But go ahead and read
what verse is that?
>> That was the end of 25.
>> Read. You shall therefore keep my
statutes and thy judgments, and shall
not commit any of these abominations,
neither any of your own nation, nor any
stranger that sojourn among you. For all
these abominations have the men of the
land done, which were before you, and
the land is defiled.
>> Yes, sir. What verse is that?
>> That was in the 27.
>> Go ahead. One more.
>> That the land spew not you out also.
>> Yes. when you defile it as it spews out
out the nations that were before you.
>> Uhoh. Now he has a balance in that. If
you do what's right, you get to stay
here. If you don't, you leave. Let's go
to uh Psalm 147th chapter. He gave them
the commandments. He said, "Guess what?
You better do what's right in that land
or else you going to get kicked out,
too." And they saw all the greatness of
God at that time.
Psalm 147, we're going to read 19 and
verse 20.
They saw this this greatness record.
That's why I said if they would have
taught us, man, we
hopefully we would have got it.
Sometimes I wonder what did Israel, what
did they do uh coming up out of the land
of Egypt?
What did they drop the kids or
something? Because it went from Abraham,
Isaac, and Jacob. All them was spotless.
They they kept the commandments.
But when it got to us, somebody is like,
"We dropped the ball." I don't know what
we did.
What Jacob did,
I have no clue. But it got to us. And
the Lord like, "Wait a minute. Hold on."
Psalm 147:1 19. Read it, brother.
>> He showeth his word unto Jacob.
>> He showeth to Jacob. What else?
>> His statutes and his judgments unto
Israel.
>> That's what we're talking about. Read,
brother.
>> He hath not dwelt dealt so with any
nation.
>> Yes.
>> And as for his judgments, they have not
known them. Yes. Praise ye the Lord.
>> Go to Amos the third chapter. Because he
gave it to us when we dealt with this
thing. Let's see what the Lord say.
Because I used to look at the people and
I say, "Hold on. I just seen people that
got away with bank robberies and all
that type of stuff."
Israel try it. You ain't no matter what
you do, where you go,
you get caught.
We going to see why you get caught doing
stuff.
Lord say the name of the game is you,
not the one.
I got my hand on you. Amos 3, pick it up
at verse one. Brother, what did it say?
>> Hear this word that the Lord has spoken
against you, oh children of Israel,
against the whole family which I brought
up from the land of Egypt, saying,
>> everybody that come up, right?
>> Read.
>> You only have I known of all the
families of the earth.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Therefore, I will punish you for all
your iniquities.
>> He said he going to punish us for all.
What about us when we get over here? Is
he going to deal with us according our
iniquities? Of course.
>> Yep.
>> He's no respect that person from
generation to generation to generations.
Let's go to Judges the third chapter.
Judges the third chapter.
And we had it. We pretty much had it
good.
We fire God. And that's crazy.
I can understand how they get tripped
up. But
at some point, if you got God that close
to you, you got to you got to deal with
it. We ain't seen all that miraculous
power like that.
And the Lord told us because our eyes
and our ears, we have not seen those
things. He said, "Blessed are they,
they have not seen, but they believe."
Yes indeed, sister.
Judges 3, pick it up at verse 12. 3 and
verse 12. Read that.
>> And the children of Israel did evil
again in the sight of the Lord.
>> Yeah, catch that. Again.
Go ahead, brother.
>> And the Lord strengthened Eglon, the
king of Moore, against Israel because
they had done evil in the sight of the
Lord.
>> So when we get out of line as a nation,
what do we do? He What's the belt? He
always got a nation in front of you.
That's a belt in his hand. Go ahead and
read, brother.
>> And he gathered unto him the children of
Aman and Amalecch.
>> Yes.
>> And went out and smoked Israel and
possessed the city of palm trees.
>> And look at that. Amalecch. They they
really happy to do it. You know why?
They are Edom seed. Edom is your twin
brother. So he can't wait to trip you
up. Go ahead and read.
>> So the children of Israel served Eglon,
the king of Moab. 18 years.
>> How many years? 18.
>> 18. And if we got it over here for five
or 10 and we can't wait for the Lord to
come look at him. 18, right? Go ahead.
>> But when the children of Israel cried
unto the Lord, the Lord raised him up, a
deliverer,
>> Eh, the son of Gera, a Benjamite, a man
left-handed, and by him the children of
Israel sent a present unto Eglon, the
king of Moab.
>> He always had somebody to do what?
Deliver you. He said, "This guy was
left-handed,
and a lot of them left-handed guys be
real thorough with that sword." So the
Lord said, "I got you." But they cried
unto the Lord. The Lord said, "I got
you."
But what did we do again? Let's go over
to chapter six.
Again and again. It's always an again
and again.
At some point, we got Well, you know
what we start doing? And I can tell our
ancestors start doing it. They were
taking God's kindness for weakness.
All right, it's okay. We might get
whooped for a little while. Just crying
to them.
Lord said, "I know the name of that
game, too." Judges 6, pick it up at
verse one. Go ahead.
>> And the children of Israel did evil in
the sight of the Lord.
>> Uhhuh. Again. Right. Go ahead.
>> Right. And the Lord delivered them into
the hand of the Midian seven years.
and the hand of Midian prevailed against
Israel. And because of the Midianites,
the children of Israel made them the
dens which are in the mountains and
caves and strongholds.
>> That's 25 years a total of captivity.
>> Just from one to another, 18, seven
earth 25. Go ahead.
>> And so it was when Israel had sown that
the Midianites came up and the Amalites
and the children of the east even they
came up against them. Look at them. They
always coming up. Look, they be happy.
Go ahead.
>> And they encamped against them and
destroyed the increase of the earth.
>> Yep.
>> Till thou come unto Gaza, and left no
substance for Israel, neither sheep, nor
ox, nor ass.
>> That's right. Go ahead.
>> For they came up with their cattle and
their tents, and they came up as
grasshoppers for a multitude. For both
they and their camels were without
number, and they entered into the land
to destroy it.
>> Yes.
And Israel was greatly impoverished
because of the Midianites. And the
children of Israel cried unto the Lord.
>> Yeah, say that. Cried again. And what
happened?
>> And it came to pass when the children of
Israel cried unto the Lord because of
the Midionites.
>> Go ahead.
>> That the Lord sent a prophet unto the
children of Israel, which said unto
them, Thus sayeth the Lord God of
Israel, I brought you up from Egypt, and
I brought you forth out of the house of
bondage.
>> Go ahead. and I delivered you out of the
hands of the Egyptians and out of the
hands of all that oppressed you and
drove them out from before you and gave
you their land.
>> Right? So he going to give him a history
lesson before he delivered him. But he
eventually delivered to him seven years.
Let's go to Proverbs the 21st chapter.
Proverbs 21st chapter
and and a lot of the times we say wait
but the but the stranger doing this they
do this and they do that now the Lord
allow them to do certain things when
they go there in the overkill the Lord
got their number
it's only a matter of time before
everybody get what they they deserve
proverb 21 we're going to read one verse
brother
21 and verse
We're going to let everybody get there.
21 and verse one.
And this Solomon, he know.
If don't nobody else know, Solomon know.
Go ahead and read verse one.
>> The king's heart is in the hand of the
Lord.
>> Wait. So they mind is where?
>> In the hand of the Lord. That's
dangerous right there cuz the Lord can
be unfair and do what? Twist you,
squeeze you. We know how that's true
because what happened in Egypt, Pharaoh
didn't want to, he didn't want to let
the people go at first. Then when he saw
all that drama happen upon the
firstborn, he told uh Moses then, "Y'all
got to go.
Y'all bring drama in the household."
Then what happened? When he wanted to
let him go, God said, "No, sir. I got a
point to prove. I'm going squeeze you.
He said his heart is in the hand of the
Lord. Go ahead.
>> As the rivers of water, he turn it
whatsoever he will.
>> Whethersoever he will, whichever way he
want you to go. Nebuchadnezzar went
crazy. Seven years.
And I can I can't imagine how this guy
was crawling around on all fours like an
animal.
and how his fingernails and feet grew
like that with them claws and eating
eating the grass and whatnot like
animals.
When he came too, he start praising God
too, didn't he?
>> Yes sir.
>> Lord apply that pressure cuz man don't
understand nothing like brother boy say
but drama. Let's go to Jeremiah the 21st
chapter.
Jeremiah the 21st
I know cuz I feel it all the time. But I
ain't going to complain either.
Take your lumps. Keep on moving.
>> Don't repeat nothing that you did that
you can think of. Wait.
No, I ain't do nothing. Hey, I was
righteous. Heck no. Let me let me
backtrack. You know, like you lost that
$5 and you turn the house up till you
find it. You got to search your mind the
same way. You flipping the c them the
pillows on the couch. You flipping them.
You reaching up under there. You feeling
crumbs and
you got cards, ink pans, tops.
You got everything on there that except
for what you looking for. Where that $5
at? Then it finally come to mind. Oh, I
I when I took my clothes off, put them
in a drop the washer. And you go in
there, you find out that $5 bill was
saved. It was a little wet, but it was
saved.
That's all we do. We search our minds.
We find out if we did something wrong.
Don't do it no more.
Jeremiah chapter 21,
21, and verse one. When you get it, go
ahead and read, brother.
>> The word which came unto Jeremiah from
the Lord.
>> Yes, sir. When King Zedekiah sent unto
him Peshu, the son of Machiah, and
Zephaniah the son of Masier the priest,
saying,
>> uhoh, read,
>> "Inquire, I pray thee of the Lord for
us. For Nebuchadnezzar, king of Babylon,
maketh war against us, if so be that the
Lord will deal with us according to all
his wondrous works, that he may go up
from us."
>> Yes, sir. So, they want Nebuchadnezzar
to leave cuz all this drama happening.
Go ahead. They they said Jeremiah unto
them,
>> uh, then say Jeremiah unto them, read.
>> Thus shall ye say to Zedekiah,
>> Yes, sir.
>> Thus saith the Lord God of Israel,
Behold, I will turn back the weapons of
war that are in your hands, wherewith
you fight against the king of Babylon,
and against the calans, which besiege
you without the walls, and I will
assemble them into the midst of this
city. So he said, "Listen, when you
fight against them, you ain't gonna win.
That's just like, I don't know if y'all
remember that
Chuck D and the uh what's the name of
that group?" Public Enemy when they was
talking, they had that song uh uh uh
what is it? Fight the powers that be.
Man, we had to I don't know about y'all,
I had the red, black, and green thing
and the fists in the air.
Come to find out when you open up the
Bible years later, you say, "Oh man, I
was fighting against the Lord."
>> No. Obey the powers that be.
>> We going to see this. Go ahead and read,
brother.
>> And I myself will fight against you with
an outstretched hand and with a strong
arm. Yes. Even in anger and in fury and
in great wrath.
>> He said, I'mma fight against you. Go
ahead. And I will smite the inhabitants
of this city, both man and beast. They
shall die of a great pestilence. Go
ahead.
>> And afterward, sayeth the Lord, I will
deliver Zedekiah, king of Judah, and his
servants and the people, and such as are
left in this city from the pestilence.
>> And we know that Zedekiah is the last
king that we had.
>> He was killed. And we know he took the
Lord took his sight away. Plus, he saw
his sons get
Man, that was a sight. Brother, go
ahead.
>> From the sword and from the famine into
the hands of Nebuchadnezzar, king of
Babylon.
>> That's the one he said that everybody
going to serve in, right?
>> Yeah.
>> He ain't say except Israel. He said all
people, all nations and languages. Go
ahead.
>> And into the hands of their enemies.
>> Yes.
>> And into the hands of those that seek
their life.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And he shall smite them with the edge of
the sword. Uh-huh.
>> He shall not spare them, neither have
pity, nor have mercy.
>> Mercy. Let's go over to Daniel the first
chapter. So, he's told them this is what
was going to happen. Let's go see. Cuz
Daniel was a survivor of this thing.
Daniel was a survivor.
Daniel chapter one.
Daniel say, "Hold on. We was in uh we
was in captivity for 70 years. What's
going on?
Lord said, "No, your calculation is
wrong."
Going to be 4 and what? 70, I think.
Said, "No, you ain't going nowhere,
brother."
Daniel, the first chapter, let's pick it
up at verse one. Chapter one, I mean
chapter. Yeah, chapter one and verse
one.
Let's look at this because he said he
was going to have Nebuchadnezzar do
this. Let's see if it actually happened.
Go ahead.
>> In the third year of the reign,
Jehookim, king of Judah, came
Nebuchadnezzar, king of Babylon, unto
Jerusalem, and besieged it. And the Lord
gave Jehookim, king of Judah, into his
hand, which part of the vessels of the
house of God, which he carried into the
land of Shinar, to the house of his God.
>> Yes, sir. And he brought his the vessels
into the treasure house of his God.
>> Yep.
>> And the king spake unto Espanas the
master of his Enoch that he should bring
certain of the children of Israel and of
the king sea and of the princes.
>> So they got all our ves. You have the
silver, you have the gold. This what his
son ended up beling
out of partying having fun. And the Lord
sent that angel.
Scared the living daylights out of that
brother. Go ahead.
>> Children in whom was no blemish, but
well favored and skillful in all wisdom.
>> They got wisdom. Go ahead, brother.
>> And cunning knowledge.
>> Yes.
>> And understanding science.
>> They wise read.
>> And such as had ability in them to stand
in the king's palace.
>> Yep.
>> And whom they might teach the learning
and tongue of the Calaldans.
>> Do we understand why they taught them
their language? Because we need you to
interpret
what we want you to do. Your slave
master always did that.
You didn't know no Hebrew or whatever
tongue when you came here.
You when you was born, they taught you
English. Say you need to know what we
want you to do as far as your task go.
Skip down to verse six. Let's see who
these children are. A few of them by
name.
Now among these were of the children of
Judah.
>> Yes.
>> Daniel, Hananiah, Masiel, Azaria.
>> So you got Mishel, Aaria, and Haniah.
Meet,
Shadrach, and Abednego. There's their
name that they changed the two. Go ahead
and read. and to whom the prince of the
Edox gave names, where he gave unto
Daniel the name of Belshazzar, and to
Haniah Shadrach and Michelle of Mach and
to Aaria of Abednego.
>> Yep. So now he told him, "Look, I'mma
change your name, too."
My name is Kevin over here. And it
probably was it would have been
something else if we had a way to the
land. Just think about it. The Lord
saying, "You getting everything
changed." Go to Jeremiah the 29th
chapter.
Jeremiah chapter 29.
Boy, I tell you, man, I knew I should
have brought them reading glasses.
Jeremiah chapter 29.
I'm straining just to see my writing.
Jeremiah 29. We're going to pick it up
at verse one.
Wait
a minute.
>> Yeah, that's
>> 7:29.
>> Jeremiah 29.
It looked like a one for a minute.
29 and verse one.
>> 29 and one. Go ahead and read, brother.
Now these are the words of the letter
that Jeremiah the prophet sent from
Jerusalem unto the residue of the elders
which were carried away captives and to
the priests and to the prophets and all
the people whom Nebuchadnezzar had
carried away captive from Jerusalem to
Babylon.
>> Yes sir. After that, Jacob Jconiah the
king and queen and the Enoch the princes
of Judah and Jerusalem
>> and the carpenters and the smiths were
departed from Jerusalem.
>> Yep. Go.
>> And in the hand of Elas, the son of
Shephan, and Gamariah the son of Ahilia,
whom Zedekiah, king of Judah, sent unto
Babylon, to Nebuchadnezzar, king of
Babylon, saying,
>> Yes. Thus says the Lord of hosts, the
God of Israel, unto all that are carried
away captives, whom I have caused to be
carried away from Jerusalem unto
Babylon.
>> Yes, sir. Go ahead, brother.
>> Build ye houses and dwell in them.
>> What' he tell you?
>> Build
a house
>> cuz you going to be there for a while.
>> What else he tell you to do?
>> And plant gardens and eat the fruit of
them.
>> Yes, sir.
Take ye wives and begat sons and
daughters.
>> Yes.
>> And take wives for your sons, and give
your daughters to husbands, that they
may bear sons and daughters, that ye may
be increased there and not diminished.
>> He ain't telling them take multiple
wives for they they sons. Cuz somebody
read that and be like, "Oh, he said
wives." No, plural for your sons.
Plural. One for each one. Especially
where we are today. Go ahead and read.
Read.
>> And seek the peace of the city where I
have caused you to be carried away
captive.
>> Oh, so if you seeking a piece of the
city, are you causing drama? Are you
being a team takeover?
Are you being a rebel of a individual
that's older? No, you shouldn't do none
of that stuff. According to what we
read, he says, "Seek the peace of the
city." Go ahead.
>> And pray unto the Lord for it.
>> Yes. For in the peace thereof shall ye
have peace.
>> Wait, so we supposed to pray pray for
this land? This what he said. Read.
>> For thus sayith the Lord of hosts, the
God of Israel.
>> Yes.
>> Let not your prophets and your dividers
that be in the midst of you deceive you.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Neither neither hearken to your dreams
which you cause to be dreamed.
>> Cuz you'll have somebody saying, "Hey, I
dreamed a dream."
Or you have your religious leaders
talking about some, hey, the Lord showed
us we got to get up out of there. No, he
didn't. He gave you certain prophecy
for you to get up out of there. If it
don't come that way, he said, don't pay
no attention to them. They trying to
deceive you. Go ahead.
>> For they prophesy falsely unto you in my
name.
>> Yes, sir.
>> I have not sent them, sayeth the Lord.
>> Oh, but they ran one more. For thus says
the Lord, that after 70 years be
accomplished at Babylon, I will visit
you and perform my good word toward you
in causing you to return to this place.
>> Wait a minute. He said they going to be
there 70 years. But wasn't Daniel in
there? Didn't Babylon, the king of
Nebuchadnezzar, take him
>> and his three comrades? Yes. But let's
see. He said 70 years. Let's go to
Daniel the ninth chapter.
Daniel said, "Hold on, wait. I know how
to count now.
70 years is up."
The Lord going to show him that ain't
what it really meant.
You got to calculate.
And they didn't have calculators back
then, but he sure had to do some
mathematics.
Daniel chapter 9, pick it up at verse
one. Now look at who's in authority. And
Daniel like, "Hold on now.
Daniel chapter 9 verse one. Go ahead and
read.
>> In the first year of Darius the son of
aosurus of the seed of the mid which was
made king over the real ram of the
calleden.
>> Yes sir.
>> In the first year of his reign. I Daniel
understood by books the number of years
whereof the word of the Lord came to
Jeremiah the prophet.
>> Understood. Wait. He understood by what?
>> Books.
>> What books? Go ahead. that he would
accomplish 70 years.
>> Wait a minute. He understood by who?
Jeremiah, right?
>> Yes.
>> Read.
>> That he would accomplish 70 years in the
desolations of Jerusalem.
>> And we just read what the Lord said that
70 years in the book of Jeremiah. Right.
>> Right.
>> Go ahead.
>> And I set my face unto the Lord God to
seek by prayer and supplications with
fasting and sackcloth and ash.
>> You see, he didn't go to none of the
older people that was there. He went to
God first. So, let me go to God about
this matter. Skip down to verse 20 and
read that verse 20. And while I was
speaking and praying and confessing my
sin and the sin of my people Israel, and
presenting my supplication before the
Lord my God for the holy mountain of my
God.
Yay. Whilst I was speaking in prayer,
even the man of Gabriel, whom I have
seen in the vision at the beginning,
being caused to fly, swiftly touched me
about the time of the evening oblation.
>> Yes, sir. What else?
>> And he informed me, and I talked with
me, and said, "Oh, Daniel, I am now come
forth to give thee skill and
understanding."
>> Yes, indeed. He said, "Now I'm coming
forth. The Lord sent me." Go ahead and
read. At the beginning of thy
supplications, the commandment came
forth, and I am come to show thee, for
thou art greatly beloved. Therefore,
understand the matter and consider the
vision. So, he had the knowledge, he had
the wisdom, but what he didn't have was
the understanding. And the Lord got to
give you that understanding. What
Solomon say about wisdom? That's the
principle thing. But he said with all
your getting get what? Understanding.
You can read some and you'll be like,
"Oh, okay. What does that mean, though?"
>> So, you need understanding of it. And
the Lord is the one that give it to you.
But what verse was that?
>> Yeah, I was in the 23.
>> Go ahead and read. We're going to read
down to 25.
>> 70 weeks are determined upon thy people
and upon thy holy city.
>> He said 70 weeks, right? Read. to finish
the transgression and to make an end of
sins and to make reconciliation for the
iniquity and to bring an everlasting
righteousness and to seal up the vision
and prophecy.
>> Isaiah 470 is 490.
But go ahead.
>> And to anoint the most holy. Know
therefore and understand that from the
going forth of the commandment to
restore and to build Jerusalem and to
the Messiah the prince shall be seven
weeks.
>> Yes.
>> And three score and two weeks.
>> Go ahead.
>> The streets shall be built up again and
the wall even in troubles time.
>> So a lot had to happen and they had to
happen. Why? Because Jesus had to come
and do what? He had to be a sacrifice
that sin that sin offering for Israel.
So the Lord knew what he was doing and
he knew that he had to restore
Jerusalem. Go to uh Daniel the 10th
chapter verse one. We're gonna read just
verse one.
Remember he said he got to anoint the
most holy which is Jesus. Then he said
the wall going to be built in troubleous
time. We're going to look at a little
bit of that too. 10 and one. Go ahead.
>> In the third year of Cyrus king of
Persia, a thing was revealed unto
Daniel.
>> Yes sir. whose name was called
Belshazzar and the thing was true but
the time appointed was long and he
understood the thing and had
understanding of the vision
>> understanding of the vision right so now
he said I understand let's go over to
Isaiah the 44th chapter Isaiah chapter
44 now when he said the wall built in
trouble times let's look who he going to
use in order to get them abide on earth
and to help them build what they need to
build for this to happen.
Then we start looking at our
governments, our people, authorities.
If you're a prime minister, you live
somewhere, you got a president, if you
got kings, watch how God work with them
on their heart.
Isaiah 44 and verse one.
We're going to read 44 verse one. Then
we're going to skip to verse 24.
Let's see who he talking to first.
Go ahead and read.
>> Yet now here, oh Jacob, my servant, and
Israel, whom I have chosen.
>> He talking about Israel, right?
>> Yes.
>> I want you to know something. Skip to 20
four.
>> Thus sayeth the Lord, thy redeemer, and
he that informed thee from the womb. I
am the Lord that maketh all things, that
stretches forth thy heavens, that maketh
all things, that stretches forth thy
heavens alone.
>> Yes.
>> That spreadth abroad the earth by
myself.
>> He said, "I'm the one. Who else did?"
Reb,
>> that frustrateth the tokens of the
liars.
>> Yes.
>> And maketh maketh divers mad.
>> That turneth wise men backward.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And maketh their knowledge foolish. Now
if you knew something and you was wise
he said you going to go backward
and then he told you about your divers
he said look they are mad now they can't
give you no vision
mad meaning upset
man I can't come up with nothing go
ahead and read
>> that confirm
>> that's like that's like your preachers
today I just had to throw that in there
but go ahead and read
>> that confirereth the word of his servant
>> yes
>> and performth the counsel of his
messengers
>> yes indeed read
>> and saith to Jerusalem, thou shalt not
be inhabited.
>> That's right.
>> And to the cities of Judah, you shall be
built.
>> Yes.
>> And I will raise up the decayed places
thereof.
>> The ones that Nebuchadnezzar destroyed.
Go ahead and read.
>> That says to the deep, "Be dry, and I
will dry up thy rivers."
>> Read. And what's happening?
>> That says to Cyrus, "He is my shepherd."
And
>> wait a minute now. Cyrus, the one that's
in in rulership, he said, "He is my
what?"
>> Shepherd.
read.
>> And shall perform all my pleasure.
>> Yes.
>> Even saying to Jerusalem, thou shalt be
built, and to the temple thy foundation
shall be laid.
>> Now the Lord said he turn the king's
heart whethersoever he will.
He made them. Look, I I made you destroy
it. I'm allow you to make sure that they
rebuild this thing. The Lord run
everything. Go to Ezra. Go to the book
of Ezra, the first chapter. as the first
chapter.
Let's look at them. He said it's going
to be built in troubleous times. We need
to see if that happened.
Prophecy.
That's what's going to get us out of
here. You have to be acquainted with
these things. You got to love to hear
it.
Might say, "Well, what this got to do
with me?" A lot.
We'll see
if we haven't already
Ezra the first chapter
and verse
one. When you get it, go ahead and read.
>> Now in the first year of Cyrus, king of
Persia, that the word of the Lord by the
mouth of Jeremiah might be fulfilled.
The Lord stirred up the spirit of Cyrus,
king of Persia.
>> Wait a minute. He said the Lord did
what? stirred up the spirit of Cyrus,
king of Persia.
>> Didn't Isaiah tell us that
>> you got to get the message from the who?
The prophets.
Go ahead and read
>> that he made a proclamation throughout
all his kingdom and put it also in
writing, saying, "Thus says Cyrus, king
of Persia, the Lord God of heaven, has
given me all the kingdoms of the earth,
and he has charged me to build him a
house at Jerusalem, which is in Judah.
Who is there among you of all his
people? His God be with him and let let
him go up to Jerusalem which is in Judah
and build the house of the Lord God of
Israel. Go ahead.
>> He is the God which is in Jerusalem.
>> He is the God which is where in
Jerusalem.
>> This guy is saying this but go ahead and
read. And whosoever remainth in any p
place where he sojour, let let the men
of his place help him with silver and
with gold and with goods and with beasts
beside the free will offering for the
house of God that is in Jerusalem.
>> Then rose up the chief of the fathers of
Judah and Benjamin and the priests and
the Levites with all them whose spirit
God had raised to go up to build the
house of the Lord which is in Jerusalem.
So you who only could touch the house
when they built it? Only Israel.
And then he definitely let you know the
priest's hands was busy.
He said the Levites, they was going to
serve them. They was going to support
the priest which is out of the tribe of
Levi. Go ahead and read.
>> And all they that were about them
strengthen their hands with vessels of
silver, with gold, with goods, and with
beasts and with precious things. Besides
all that was willingly offered.
>> What else? One more verse.
>> Also Cyrus the king brought forth the
vessels of the house of the Lord which
Nebuchadnezzar had brought forth out of
Jerusalem and had put them in the house
of his God.
>> He took it, didn't he? And then he said,
"We're going to bring it back cuz it
belonged to who?" God just like the
nations got our stuff now. He said, "You
gonna get it back."
But I ain't I ain't gonna lie. I ain't
really interested in that. I just want
to make sure that I get it. It's
salvation. Let's go to Daniel the third
chapter.
Gold and silver and all that is good.
But what's better is you becoming God at
that moment and you don't have to worry
about none of that. Daniel the third
chapter.
I like the best deal, not the a good
deal. The best
Go ahead and read uh Daniel chapter 3.
Pick it up at verse one. Brother
Nebuchadnezzar the king made an image of
gold whose height was three score cubits
and the breadth thereof six cubits. He
set it up in the palm of Dura, plain of
Dura.
>> Yes, sir.
>> In the province of Babylon.
>> Go ahead. Then Nebuchadnezzar the king
sent to gather together the princes, the
governors and the captains, the judges,
the treasurers, the counselors, the
sheriffs, and all the rulers of the
province.
>> You ain't got to read all that. Skip
down to verse four, brother. Verse four,
read that.
>> Then and Harold cried aloud to you. It
is command that oh people, nations and
language that at what time you hear the
sounds of the cornet, flute, harp,
sackbutt, sultry, doulamer, and all
kinds of music, you shall you fall ye
fall down and worship the golden image
that Nebuchadnezzar the king has set up.
>> Uh oh. He said, I want you to make sure
that you worship this thing. So if you
in this land and they tell you to do
this, you supposed to rebel against
that. So it's certain things that they
tell you to do and then there certain
things that go against God that you
don't do. You have to die for this
thing. Go ahead and read, brother.
>> And whosoever fallth not down and
worship shall the same hour be cast into
the midst of a burning fiery furnace.
>> Uhhuh. What verse was that?
>> That was the end of six.
>> Okay, skip down to verse eight. Verse
eight. Read it. Wherefore at the time
certain called deans came near and
accused the Jews.
>> They did what? Accused the Jews, didn't
they? Yes. Skip to verse 12.
>> There are certain Jews whom thou has set
over the affairs of the providence of
Babylon. Shadrach, Meach, and Abedneo.
These men, oh king, have not regarded
thee. They serve not thy gods, nor
worship the golden image which thou hast
set up.
>> Yeah, I want the definition of snitch.
And look at that.
You over there serving your God ain't
snitching.
First snitches that I Well, ain't the
first, but look at them snitches. Go
ahead.
>> Then Nebuchadnezzar in his rage and fury
commanded to bring Shadrach, Meshach,
and Abedneo.
Then they had brought these men before
the king.
>> Yes. Go ahead. One more. Nebuchadnezzar
spake and said unto them, "Is it true,
oh Shadrach, Meshach, and Abedneo, do
you not ye serve my gods, nor worship
the golden image which I have set up?"
>> Skip to 8:16. Now, verse 16, read it.
>> Shadrach, Meshach, and Abednego answered
and said to the king, "Oh
Nebuchadnezzar, we are not careful to
answer thee in this matter."
>> So, we we're not a going to hesitate. Go
ahead. If it be so, our God whom we
serve is able to deliver us from the
burning fiery furnace.
>> He didn't say will deliver us. He said
he's able though.
>> So it may not go thy way and they have
understanding to know that.
You can't say, man, you know what? God
gonna deliver me. What if he don't?
Then you like, oh, wait a minute. Let my
hands get weak. My mind is very weary
and I'm faint now. Now I'm gonna do
something I ain't supposed to do.
Go ahead and read, brother. What else?
>> And he will deliver us out of thy hand,
O king.
>> Yes.
>> But if not, be it known unto thee, O
king, that we will not serve thy gods.
>> What else?
>> Nor worship the golden image which thou
hast set up.
>> They say they're not going to do that.
Right.
>> Right.
>> Let's go to Hebrews the 12th chapter.
But he ended up doing it. But we we'll
see that. But let's go to uh Hebrews the
12th chapter because we're in captivity
now. Sometimes it don't even feel like
it to people that don't know.
Like what you talking about captivity,
man? I can do what I want. I got money,
job, bank account, house, car.
You don't have your freedom.
Hebrews chapter 12. Pick it up at verse
two. Hebrews chapter 12 and verse
two. What about when you need to go
drive? You got to drive that car. You
got you got to get a driver's license.
Now you got to have insurance.
Then they say, "Forget that uh
I forget the name of it, but they want
you to have full coverage." Now
liability. used to get away with that
cheap one. They said, "No, you going to
get full coverage
or if we catch you, we're going to
ticket you and then you you can risk
getting your license taken. Then you
have to be on a bus."
Lord said, "You going to serve your
enemy for the want of all things."
Hebrews 12 and verse two, brother, what
it say?
>> Looking unto Jesus, the author and
finisher of our faith.
>> Wait a minute. He's the one that started
this thing. He going to end it. Our
faith. Go ahead.
>> Who for the joy that was set before him
endured the cross.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Despising the shame and is sat down at
the right hand of the throne of God.
>> So he was going through suffering. Read.
>> For consider him that endured such
contradiction of sinners against
himself.
>> Against who? Himself. Read.
>> Lest you be worried and faint in your
mind.
>> See that? I was talking about that
earlier. Read one more. We have not yet
resisted unto blood, striving against
sin.
>> Wait, wait. He said you ain't resist no
blood yet. Who took you and said you
going to put yourself in them stocks?
Who put you in prison for your faith
just because you believe in this book.
You don't deal with sodomy. You don't
deal with unclean foods. You don't deal
with certain holiday.
They like, "Oh, no. You got to come on."
And you like, "What did I do? I'm I'm
keeping I'm being peaceful at my own
house, in my city. What did I do? You
ain't serving our God. Who going through
this?
We getting tongue lashes and we be bent
out of shape.
Hey man, I give up. This thing is not
for me." Well, what what doctrine you
going to go to that going to give you
what you need?
>> Let's go to the book of Acts. He say you
have not resisted unto blood.
So when they tell you to do this, let's
go to Acts the 5th chapter.
Peter going to tell you exactly what to
do
as he was walking during the time of
Jesus and he knew he was going through
it.
Rumor has it. Notice I said rumor has it
that Peter was crucified just like
Jesus. However, he said he wanted to be
crucified upside down.
And they asked him why. I don't want to
be mistaken for Jesus.
I said it's a Roma, but it sounds like
it would be something that's wise to say
if he did come through. Cuz Israel said
they be like, "Oh, that wasn't Jesus
before." That's Jesus.
It's upside down. That can't be him.
Acts 5, pick it up at verse 17. Let's
see what happened.
Go ahead, brother.
>> Then the high priest rose up and all
they that were with him, which is the
sect of the Sadducees,
>> Yes.
>> and were filled with indignation. And
the Sadducees, they don't believe in
what? The resurrection.
>> They don't believe in angels, spirits,
none of that.
And this is what he believe in. So you
know what he dealing with? Go ahead.
>> And laid their hands on the apostles.
>> Oh, beat on them. Read.
>> And put them in the common prison.
>> Who went through this? Go ahead.
>> But the angel of the Lord by night
opened the prison doors.
>> Yes. and brought them forth and said,
>> "Go, stand and speak in the temple to
the people all the words of this life."
>> What else?
>> And when they had heard that, they
entered into the temple early in the
morning and taught. But the high priest
came, and they that were with him, and
called the council together, and all the
senate of the children of Israel, and
sent them to prison to have them
brought.
>> And sent them to prison to have them
what?
>> Brought.
>> Brought. bring them to me. Skip down to
verse uh 26 and read.
>> Then went the captain with the officers
and brought them without violence. For
they feared the people lest they should
have been stoned.
>> Yes, sir. Brother G.
>> And when they had brought them, they set
before them. They set before them the
council. And the high priest asked them,
saying, did not we straightly command
you that you should not teach in this
name?
>> In what name? his name.
It may not sound like Jesus, but it was
a name not familiar today, God. Read.
>> And behold, you have filled Jerusalem
with your doctrine and intend to bring
this man's blood upon us.
>> He said, "Wait a minute. You going to
fill Jerusalem with this blood
and this doctrine?
Cuz guess what? You going to end up jack
you going to end up having the Lord come
against us." What Peter say after that?
Go ahead.
>> Then Peter and the other apostles
answered and said, "We ought to obey God
rather than men."
>> Wait a minute. Y'all see that? He said,
"We got to obey God rather than men."
But we see what it was referring to.
Right.
>> Right.
>> Skip on down to 33 and read that.
>> When they heard that, they were cut to
the heart and took counsel to slay them.
Then stood there up one in the council,
a Pharisee named Gamma. Gavalo. Yes,
sir.
>> A doctor of the law and had an
reputation among all the people, and
commanded to put the apostles forth a
little space.
>> These were the This is the individual
that taught uh Paul, go
>> and said unto them, "Ye men of Israel,
take heed to yourselves that you intend
to do as touch touching these men."
>> Yeah.
>> For before these days rose up Theodus,
boasting himself to be somebody. Yes
sir. Go ahead.
>> To whom a number of men about 400 joined
themselves who were slain and all as
many as obeyed him were scattered and
brought to not.
>> Go ahead read.
>> After this man rose up Judas of Galilee
in the days of the taxing and drew away
much people after him. He also perished
and all even as many as obeyed him were
dispersed.
>> Yes indeed. And spirit of them Pharisees
was doing what? Driving people away from
the Lord. Go ahead and read.
>> And now I say unto you, refrain from
these men and let them alone.
>> Go ahead.
>> For if this council or this work be of
men, it will come to none.
>> He said, so now if Peter and them saying
something that ain't supposed to be
true, it's going to come to nothing. But
if at last, you know it's from God. So
you better stand back and don't make
sure you don't fight against who? God.
Because you fighting against God. Go
ahead and read. But if it be if it be of
God, ye cannot overthrow it.
>> That's right. Go ahead.
>> Lest happily ye be found even to fight
against God. Yes, sir. Go ahead.
>> And to him they agreed. And when they
had called the apostles and beaten them,
they commanded that they should not
speak in the name of Jesus and let them
go.
>> Oh, beaten them. Yeah, I ain't trying to
feel that, but go ahead.
and they departed from the presence of
the council, rejoicing that they were
counted worthy to suffer shame for his
name.
>> And I ain't going to lie, I I've
suffered beatings for less way less than
that. I just ask the Lord give me
strength if I have to go through that.
Go to Daniel the 5th chapter. Daniel
chapter 5. If I got to go through it,
Lord, strengthen me.
When I was running the streets, I did
it. So, hey, shouldn't be no different.
Just make sure they don't put me to
death
and make sure they don't hurt me
permanently,
that I can recover.
Daniel chapter 5 verse one, we going to
look at what uh
happened here with uh Bel Shazar.
This is uh
Nebuchadnezzar's son.
Pick it up at verse chapter 5 verse one.
Brother
>> Belshazzer the king made a great feast
to a thousand of his lords and drank
wine before the thousand.
>> We I spoke about this earlier. Go ahead
and read.
>> Belshazzer while he tasted the wine
commanded to bring the golden and silver
vessels which his father Nebuchadnezzar
had taken out of the temple which was in
Jerusalem.
>> What else? that the king and his
princes, his wives, and his concubines
might drink therein.
>> What else?
>> Then they brought the golden vessels
which were taken out of the temple of
the house of God, which was at
Jerusalem. And the king and his
princess, his wives, and his concubines
drank in them.
>> What else?
>> They drank wine and praised the gods of
gold and of silver, of brass, of iron,
of wood, of stone.
>> Yes, sir. And what else? In the same
hour came forth fingers of a man's hand
and wrote over against the candlestick
upon the plaster of the wall of the
king's palace. And the king saw the part
of the hand that ro.
>> Now we know that the angels got hands
too. He said like the man's hands. So
from up under them wings just that hand
is going to appear. And this guy said
what in the world? Go ahead and read
brother. Then the king's countenance was
changed.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And it starts troubled him.
>> Now he just talking about his facial
figure.
You know, you go from partying and
relaxed to what the
>> your face to change.
Go ahead and read what's going on. Read.
>> So that the joints of his loins were
loose
>> and his knees smoke one against another.
>> Now I ain't never seen nobody do this,
but on the cartoons I did.
Y'all know how they did on a
>> and you like I only thought that was in
the cartoons, but it actually happened.
Go ahead.
>> The king cried aloud to bring in the
stousers, the Calaldanss, and the
soussayers.
>> Yes. And the king spake and said to the
wise men of Babylon, "Whosoever shall
read this writing and show me the
interpretation thereof shall be clothed
with scarlet and have a chain of gold
about his neck and shall be the third
ruler in the kingdom."
>> Yes sir. Skip down to verse uh 18 and
read.
>> Oh thou king the most high God gave
Nebuchadnezzar thy father a kingdom and
majesty and glory and honor. What else?
>> And for the majesty that he gave him,
all people, nations, and languages
trembled before him, whom he would would
whom he would slew. Yeah. And whom he
would who he would
>> kept alive. Yep.
>> And whom he would has set up and whom he
would put down.
>> So in other words, he can call the shots
almost like God in this earth.
He said if he want to kill you, he got
the free reign. If he want to set you
up, he can do it. If he want to put you
down, he can do it. That's why the Lord
say, "Make sure that you obey these guys
because I gave him authority to kill
the angels." He did it when we was
coming up out of the land of Egypt. He
said, "Listen, you better obey them
because guess what? It's in them to do
what? Kill you if you don't." And he
told them, "Look, if they turn right or
left, kill them."
>> Right?
>> The angel don't know nothing else except
what God told him to do.
>> And guess what? We fought against that.
But what verse is that, brother?
>> That was the end of the 19.
>> Go ahead and read that. But when his
heart was lifted up and his mind
hardened in pride, he was disposed from
his kindly throne, and they took his
glory from him. And he was driven from
the sons of men, and his heart was made
like the beast, and his dwelling was
with the wild asses. They fed him with
grass like oxen, and his body was wet
with the dew of heaven. Till he knew
that the most high God ruled in the
kingdom of men.
>> Yes, sir. and that he appointeth over it
whomsoever he will.
>> So he running it down to him. Go ahead.
>> And thou his son, and though his son, O
Belshazzar, has not humbled thine heart,
though thou kneest all this.
>> You know this stuff. Why didn't you
humble it? Skip down to verse 25 and
read.
>> And this is the writing that was
written. Many, many teel a parson. This
is an interpretation of the thing. Many
God hath numbered thy kingdom and
finished it. Tequel thou art weighed in
the balances and are found wanting.
Paris the king is divided and given to
the Mes and the Persians.
>> Yes, sir. Is given over to them. Read.
Then commanded Belshazzar, and they
clothed Daniel with scarlet, and put a
chain of gold about his neck, and made a
proclamation concerning him that he
should do the third that he should be
the third ruler in the kingdom.
>> Yep.
>> And this night was Belshazzar,
the king of Calaldian slain. And Darius
the Median took the kingdom being about
three score and two years old.
>> Yep. So now
after him the Greeks rule well after the
whole kingdom of the Mes and the
Persians. Then you had the Greeks rule
with Alexander and his generals after he
didn't died which he was pretty young
when he died. Then you had Rome coming
up picture. Let's go to Matthew chapter
19.
And this is why they kingdom that uh
land was given back to Israel. And they
raised up,
you know, the priests to do their jobs.
They was given the vessels so they could
carry out these duties cuz Jesus had to
come. Matthew 19 and pick it up at verse
16.
19 and verse 16.
Let's look at something real quick.
This guy from asked Jesus a question.
Let's see what he asked him. Go ahead
and read.
>> And behold, one came and said unto him,
"Good master, what good thing shall I do
that I may have eternal life?"
>> I need to know what shall I do that I
might have eternal life? Go ahead.
>> And he said unto him,
>> Why callst thou me good?
>> Yes, sir.
>> There is none good but one.
>> There is none,
>> that is God. He said, "There is none
good but one,
>> that is God." Read.
>> But if thou would enter into life, keep
the commandments.
>> And what did we start off reading today?
The commandments.
I think that's a small
thing to do to become this great
individual and being
that's small. Even though we know this
flesh is always troubling us. Go ahead
and read. He saith unto him, which Jesus
said, "Thou shalt do do no murder."
>> That's right.
>> Thou shalt not commit adultery. Thou
shalt not steal. Thou shall not bear
false witness.
>> Yes.
>> Honor thy father and thy mother.
>> Thou shalt not love thy neighbor as thy
thou shalt love thy neighbor as thyself.
>> Now, so look, we see, thou shalt do no
murder.
We shall do no murder. Right.
>> Right.
And we look at that and then we tell
people, you know what? You ain't got the
right to defend yourself because the
Lord say, "Thou shall not kill or
murder." Let's go look at it real quick.
Exodus the 28th chapter
cuz he going to say, "Thou not," we
gonna see what he's saying when he say
that, "Thou shall not kill." He gonna
say it.
Exodus the 20th chapter. I just threw
that in because I knew it's certain
things you can do over in the land.
One of them is defend yourself.
If people if somebody come and do
something to you, that means you know
somebody going to break in your house,
steal something. They trying to hurt you
and your spouse, your children. I know
I'm not going to sit there. I don't know
about nobody else.
Exodus 20, read that 13 verse. Let's see
what he say again.
Exodus 20:13. We read this earlier. Read
it again.
Exodus 20:13,
>> "Thou shalt not kill."
>> Yep. He said, "Thou shall not what?
Kill." We read that and say, "Hold on."
But he said, "Murder, premeditated."
You going to do something to somebody
that ain't you ain't supposed to. Now,
if they come up on you and do some harm,
better protect yourself. Let's look at
somebody who did. Let's go to Psalm 144.
Let's look at somebody who did that.
And he going to say, "Who taught him how
to do it?"
We should know by now. That's David.
David said, "Uhuh."
>> Cuz when Goliath came up against him,
what'd he do?
Kill.
>> Kill him.
>> Psalm 144 and verse one.
Let's see what uh David say. Go ahead.
>> Bless be the Lord my strength.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Which teacheth my hands to war.
>> Teacheth my hands to do what?
>> To war.
>> But even though he was taught, even
though he had do that, but he said the
Lord teach my hands to war. Go ahead.
>> And my fingers to fight.
>> What else, brother?
>> My goodness and my fortress, my high
tower and my deliverer, my shield. And
he in whom I trust. Who subdueth my
people under me. who subdueth my people
under me. He acknowledging God. He said,
"I can do none of this if I wanted to
without God." Let's go to First
Chronicles. Look at something he said
over here.
First Chronicles. Well, something he did
First Chronicles. And again, I threw
that in because I always heard people
say, "You can't do that. You're a
Christian. We don't do that.
Turn the other cheek. What you talking
about?
Somebody trying to take you out for the
name of Jesus, you can't do nothing to
him
cuz you got to suffer for his name's
sake. He's going to put you on trial.
But if it's for something else, that's
why I say you got to read and get
understanding
or else you be stuck.
They come in my house. Oh, slap this
face on their side. Slap it on their
side, man. When they put you under,
you'll be like, "Man,
what happened when the Lord raised you
up? You died. You allowed him to do
what? Kill you.
You had the power to defend yourself."
1 Chronicles 14, pick it up at verse
one.
No, I'm sorry. Verse two.
14 and verse two. Read that, brother.
>> And David perceived that the Lord had
confirmed. I stand there pages.
He said he he teaches my hands to war my
fingers to fight.
And David perceived that the Lord had
confirmed him king over Israel.
>> Yes.
>> For his kingdom was lifted up on high.
>> Now be because of his people Israel.
>> Because of his people Israel. Didn't he
say that the Lord subdued him unto me?
Skip to verse uh 8. Verse eight and
read.
>> And when the Philistines heard that
David was anointed king over all Israel,
all the Philistines went up to seek
David. And David heard of it and went
out against them.
>> Yes, sir.
Go ahead.
>> And and the Philistines came and spread
themselves in the valley of Reaper. And
David inquired of God, saying, "Shall I
go up against the Philistines?" Say
that. Shall I go up against them? Go
ahead.
>> And wilt thou deliver them into mine
hand?
>> Because if you don't, I'm willing to die
for what you saying. Read.
>> And the Lord said unto him, "Go up, for
I will deliver them into thine hand."
So they came up to Bob Perisen, and
David spoke to him there.
Then David said, "God has broken broken
in upon mine enemies by mine hand like
the breaking forth of waters." Therefore
they called the name of this place Val
Perisen.
>> Yes sir. What verse you read, brother?
I'm sir.
>> That was in the 11.
>> Go ahead.
>> And when they had laid their gods before
there, they gave a commandment and they
were burned with fire.
>> Yes, sir. Go ahead.
>> And the Philistines yet again spread
themselves abroad in the valley.
Therefore, David inquired of God, and
God said unto him, "Go not up after
them. Turn away from them and come."
Y'all notice every time he always
inquire of God, right? Pray to the Lord
if that's the step that you need to
take. Go ahead.
Go ahead.
>> And come upon them over against the
malberry tree.
>> Yes, sir.
And it shall be when thou hast when thou
and And it shall be when thou shalt hear
a sound of going in the tops of the
malberry trees, then thou shalt go out
to battle. For God has gone forth before
thee to smite the host of the
Philistines.
>> So when you defend yourself, who is it
that's giving you that power and that
might to him?
>> God.
>> God. That's why I say that. Go ahead and
read.
>> David therefore did as God commanded
him. And they smoked the host of the
Philistines from Gibon even to Gazer.
>> Yeah, this is him just going to war. But
go ahead, read verse 17.
>> And the fame of David went out unto all
lands. And the Lord God, and the Lord
brought to the fear of him upon all
nations.
>> Now, everybody heard about David and
they scared. They said, "This guy wields
the sword, brother. He killing people
who we thought would never die.
They was going to live on forever."
Let's go to Romans the 13th chapter.
Romans chapter 13.
Why is he telling us to uh submit
ourselves? He said it's for your own
good.
That's why when you pull over there and
the first thing they tell you is you
need to let the authorities know that
you have a firearm.
Let them know
so they don't get jumpy cuz they will
take you out.
They won't hesitate.
You talking about an itchy trigger
finger.
Romans 13, pick it up at verse one,
brother. What it say? Let every soul be
subject unto the high power.
>> Some souls.
>> Every soul.
>> Yes. No matter where you are. Go ahead.
>> For there is no power but of God.
>> He set it up. If you exist, he set you
up. Go ahead.
>> The powers that be are ordained of God.
>> Yes, sir. Read.
>> Whosoever thereof resisteth the power
resisteth the ordinance of God.
>> What else?
>> And they that resist shall receive to
themselves damnation. And what else,
brother? For rulers are not a terror to
good works.
>> So if we say no, I'm not going to do
that or I ain't gonna do this. The Lord
say I'm going to get you and pretty much
it's going it's going to hurt you in the
end. But go ahead and read.
>> But to the evil will thou wil thou then
not be afraid of the power. Do that
which is good and thou shalt have praise
of the same. He said, "So if you are
evil," he said, "you better duck in his
alley and make sure cuz you know a lot
of people don't have their plates right,
>> they riding around with temp tags from
10 years ago." I'm telling y'all because
I still see it to this day and I be
like, man, but guess what? They on all
the side streets.
Why? They afraid.
He said, "You better be cuz they going
to take you to jail."
And if you don't comply, they gonna take
you somewhere else you don't want to be.
He said, "Then you'll have praise of the
saint." They'll be happy they get to go
home without killing nobody to their
family. Read, brother. What else?
>> For he is the minister of God, to thee
for good.
>> Wait a minute. To you for good. He is a
minister of God. Go ahead.
>> But if thou do that which is evil,
>> Uhhuh.
>> be afraid.
>> Yes, sir.
>> For he beareth not the sword in vain. He
will kill you. Go ahead.
>> For he is the minister of God.
>> He work. We read that. That's why we
went to Cyrus building allowing him to
build up what? Jerusalem. And they
dealing in trouble times.
We could have kept reading and saw them
building a wall in Ezra and how they
kept coming up on coming up on them.
They had to put their weapons down with
the tools and instruments down fight
them.
Then the Lord actually allowed them to
get taken out so that they can build it.
But go ahead and read what? What verse?
>> It was that middle of four. A revenger
to execute wrath upon him that doeth
evil.
>> Yeah. The Lord said, I sent them up.
What did he tell Israel? I brought you
by the land of Egypt, all the families
of the earth. He said, listen, I for you
if you said I'm going to kill you. In
other words, your iniquities, they gonna
be found. That's why I say, "How come we
always get caught?"
It ain't that Israel ain't good
criminals. Well, ain't no such thing as
a good criminal.
>> Cuz the Lord say Israel is wise to do
evil.
>> So you can have a mind to do
wrong and be real strategic in it.
>> So don't think it don't happen. But he
said, guess what he said? I got this guy
set up specifically for you.
Go ahead and read verse five.
>> Wherefore ye must needs be subject.
>> Wait. Must and needs. Two absolute
words. Right.
>> Yes.
>> Must the needs be what? Subject. Go
ahead.
>> Not only for wrath.
>> Not just for wrath because they'll kill
you. What else?
>> But also for conscious sake.
>> So you ain't got to worry about it. So
when they pull us over, we don't be
weary. When we in his faith, we like,
"All right, let me see your license and
registration. There you go."
Even if something is expired real quick
and you know you got to take care of it,
you ain't going to talk crazy to them.
You already know what can happen. But go
ahead and read because a lot of them
say, "You know what? Listen, just get it
take care of. I'm, you know, I'm let you
off with a warning. That's it." They be
fighting. Look, I ain't got to roll down
my window. I know this law and that law
and they're like, "All right, I'm
telling you, get out that vehicle."
I watched that a little bit and I said,
"I can't see the end of this cuz I know
it ain't going to turn out good."
I don't want to see my people getting
killed. Go ahead and read.
>> For this cause, pay ye tribute also.
>> Yes, sir.
>> For they are God's ministers, attending
continually upon this very thing.
>> Now, we got to pay we got to pay what?
Taxes. Go ahead. Render therefore to all
their dues.
>> Yes sir.
>> Tribute to whom tribute is due. Custom
to whom? Custom. Fear to whom? Fear.
Honor to whom honor. You got taxes on
food that you buy now. And it wasn't
like that at first. A dollar for
whatever it costs.
Now they say a$147.
So now you got to break off that $147.
You got taxes for property that you own,
taxes for that. You got to pay taxes off
your wages. You got tax for everything.
He said, "Make sure you pay them, folk."
Go ahead.
>> Oh, no man anything.
>> No. Oh,
>> but to love one another.
>> Yes, sir. What else?
>> For he that loveth another hath
fulfilled the law.
>> Now, let's go to Matthew chapter 22.
Because Jesus said it, but he also did
it himself.
Him and Peter.
When you ain't got no money and you God,
you can do this right here. Matthew
chapter 22.
But what I mean is you ain't got no
money on you.
And you know they looking for it.
Start at verse four 15
22 and verse 15. I got 17 but start at
15 so we can understand why he said what
he said. Go ahead.
>> Then went the Pharisees and took counsel
how they might entangle him in his talk.
>> Yes sir, brother. They looking to
entangle you. Go ahead. And they sent
out unto him their disciples with the
Herodians, saying, Master, we know that
thou art true, and teachest the way of
God in truth. Neither carest thou for
any man, for thou regard not the person
of men.
>> That's right. What else?
>> Tell us, therefore, what thinkst thou?
Is it lawful to give tribute unto Caesar
or not?
>> Wait a minute. Is it lawful to give
tribute unto Caesar?
Well, the Romans, they are the Gentiles,
right? They the ones that's ruling
during Jesus time. Of course, it's
legal. He just said, "Olawful to do it."
Read.
>> Cuz they wanted the entanglement in his
word. Go ahead and read, brother.
>> But Jesus perceived their wickedness and
said, "Why temptestth ye me?"
>> Why you tempted me, brother? Go ahead.
>> You hypocrites?
>> Yes.
>> Show me the tribute money.
>> And they brought unto him a penny. And
he saith unto them, Who is this image
and subscription? And they said unto
him, Caesars.
>> Yes.
>> Then saith he unto them, Render
therefore unto Caesar the things which
are Caesars.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And unto God the things that are God.
>> Yes indeed. One more.
>> When they had heard these words, they
marveled and left him and went their
way.
>> Now you trying to entangle him. He
dropped you with some knowledge. Let's
back up to chapter 17. And they was
scratching their head.
How this dude know everything?
Cuz they knew the answer to it. They
just want to see if he did.
We going to catch them up one of these
days, not today.
17 and verse 24. 17 and 24. Let's see
what he did now. Go ahead.
>> And when they were come to Capernaum,
they had received tribute money came to
Peter and they said, "Doth not you, your
master pay tribute? Don't your m wait
don't they pay tribute? Go ahead.
>> He says yes. And when he was come into
the house, Jesus prevented him, saying,
"What thinkst thou, Simon?"
>> Yes.
>> "Or whom do the kings of the earth take
custom or tribute?"
>> Go ahead.
>> Of their own children or of strangers?
>> Yeah. Believe. Peter saith unto him of
strangers, Jesus saith unto him, then
are the children free, notwithstanding,
lest we should offend them, goes out to
the sea, and cast on hook.
>> Now, he telling you to go to the sea,
cast a hook, and it ain't going to be no
fish coming up, not for you to eat. Go
ahead.
>> And take up the fish that first cometh
up.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And when thou has opened his mouth, thou
shall find a piece of money.
>> You going to find a piece of money. Go
ahead. that take and give unto them for
me and thee.
>> I wonder if Peter was like, "Hey man, I
need to do this more often."
Because you know, Peter fished. So Peter
was like, "Here go the, you know, I got
the money for them so they can pay the
people and they won't offend the
Gentiles." Because if you offend them,
what they going to do? Come after you.
First Peter, and they gonna kill you. Go
to First Peter the second chapter. Jesus
told you, "I'm doing it. Why you ain't
doing it?
What's the problem?
These people will get you.
Then we going to look at the We going to
look real quick at the uh
the ones that
the ones that uh that are doing the
takeover. 1 Peter 2 and 11. Read that
real quick, brother.
First Peter chapter 2. Yeah. First
Peter.
>> Okay. Chapter 2 and verse 11.
>> Dearly beloved, I beseech you as
strangers and pilgrims, abstain from
fleshly lust, which war against the
soul, having your conversation honest
among the Gentiles, that whereas they
speak against you as evildoers, they may
be your that they may be your good
works, which they shall behold.
>> That they may what?
>> Glorify God.
>> That they may what? see your good works
that they by your good works which they
shall What verse you at?
>> Uh middle of 12.
>> Go ahead.
>> That they may by your good works which
they shall behold.
>> Yes, sir.
>> glorify God in the day of visitation.
>> That's how he said in the book of
Romans. He told you, listen, they going
they going to praise God for this if you
obey him. Go ahead and read.
>> Submit yourselves to every ordinance of
man for the Lord's sake. Yes, sir. What
else?
>> Whether it be to the king as supreme.
>> Yep.
>> Or unto governors as unto them that are
sent by him for the punishment of
evildoers.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And for the praise of them that do well.
>> You got jobs. And if your boss, your
supervisor, your manager, shift manager
tell you something, you can't snap go
off.
>> You got to obey. This is what he telling
us. Everybody that's in authority
You got children. Children supposed to
listen to their parents. He said, "Honor
your father and your mother." The Lord
looking at all of them because guess
what? You can take the belt off and deal
with them kids.
Then they'll understand the power that
you have over them. Go ahead and read.
>> For so is the will of God that with
welldoing you may put to silence the
ignorance of foolish men.
>> Yes. Just like Jesus did, didn't he had
him apostle?
Well, not the apostles. The Pharisees
and the Herodians walk away. Yes,
indeed. Put the sign as they
foolishness. Go ahead.
>> As free. And not using your liberty for
a cloak of malice.
>> Yeah.
>> But as a servants of God,
>> right? He said, not using your cloak of
>> maliciousness.
>> Of maliciousness. But as a servants of
God, you know, you got this this
understanding. Don't try to use it to
your benefit to do certain things. And
you know these people gonna come up on
you. Go ahead. Honor all men. Love the
brotherhood. Fear God. Honor the king.
>> Wait a minute. He said, "Honor the
brotherhood, fear God,
>> and honor the king." Skip down to verse
21.
No, 18. Read 18. I'm sorry. Verse 18.
>> Servants, be subject to your masters.
Yeah. With all fear.
>> Not only
>> Not only to the good and gentle, but
also to the forward.
>> Right. So, we got the supervisor. That's
cool.
We got the manager that's cool, but when
we get the one that talk crazy, we be
upset. He said, not only to the good and
gentle, but also to the fraud. They talk
crazy,
you'll lose your
your tokens for that. You don't want to
lose your money.
Then you be at home like, "God, bless me
with another job." You're like, "No, you
just walked off and you supposed to be
doing that.
I want them to see the example of a
servant. Plus, they are over you. Act
like it. Then it's somebody that look
like you. They get their little job and
they oh man,
you be like, "Oh no, brother. I ain't
going to take that." Oh, sister. Who you
talking to with that attitude?
Then you have proper steps and channels
that you can go to. But they say human
resources and all the different people,
>> right? You can go and properly
address the issue, but you can't go back
and forth with these people because they
can do something to you. Is they word
over yours? Skip down to verse 21,
brother.
>> For even here unto we called.
>> Were ye called? Go ahead.
>> Because Christ also suffered for us,
>> leaving us what?
>> Leaving us an example that ye should
follow his steps.
>> Yes, sir. What else?
>> Who do no sin
>> who did no sin. Neither was G found in
his mouth.
>> That's right. What else?
>> Who? When he was reviled, reviled not
again. When he suffered, he threatened
not.
>> That's right.
>> But committed himself to him that judges
righteously.
>> Yep. Let's go look at Jesus doing that.
John the 19th chapter. We only got a
couple of more. John chapter 19.
He said he didn't say nothing, right? He
said he left it up to God the Father.
cuz he going to let Jesus come back and
deal with these guys.
He could have threw her in a towel and
said, "Uh, send me
12 legions of angels.
I don't know how many that is, but
it's enough to get the job done.
One angel can do destruction. You going
to send 12 legion? You talking about
turn the whole world up."
John 19, pick it up at verse one.
Go ahead.
>> Then Pilate therefore took Jesus and
scourged him.
>> Scourged him. Go ahead.
>> And the soldiers platted a crown of
thorns and put it on his head.
>> Yes.
>> And they put him they put on him a
purple robe.
>> Yes, sir. What else?
>> And he said, "Hail, King of the Jews."
And they smoked him with their hands.
Pilate therefore went forth again and
saith un unto them, Behold, I bring him
forth to you, that you may know that I
find no fault in him.
>> Yes, indeed. What else?
>> Then came Jesus forth wearing the crown
of thorns and the purple robe. And
Pilate said to him, "Behold the man."
Then the chief priest therefore and
officers saw him. They cried out,
saying, "Crucify him! Crucify him."
Pilot saith unto them, "Take ye him and
crucify him." Yes. For I find no fault
in him.
>> Now, I didn't mention this, but what if
you the boss? What if you the
supervisor? You can't torture nobody
either, man. Now, I'm on top. Yeah, I'll
do what I say. Go to get it, man. People
going to be looking at you like, "Hold
on, bro. Why you doing me like that?"
Because I got the power. The Lord will
come down on you. So, you got to be
careful on both ends,
>> right?
Then what if you have your own? Because
we got our own businesses in this world.
People got corporations.
You got it like that. You got to be
careful. You can't do certain things to
Israel or the Gentile.
>> Right.
>> Go ahead and read that, brother.
>> Then Jesus answered him, "We have a law,
and by our law he ought to die because
he has made himself the son of God."
>> Yes, sir. What else? When Pilate
therefore heard that saying, he was the
more afraid and went again into the
judgment hall and saith unto Jesus,
Whence art thou? But Jesus gave him no
answer.
>> Which are you where you come from, man?
Who are you? He said Jesus gave him no
answer. Skip down to verse.
>> Well, we right there. Read verse 10.
>> Then say Pilate unto him, Speakst thou
not unto me?
>> That's right. Knowest thou not that I
have power to crucify thee, and have
power to release thee?
>> Look at what he say. He got power that
got the authority to do. I can cruc I
can crucify you or I can release you.
Why ain't you saying nothing? Read verse
11. Jesus going to open up his mouth. Go
ahead.
>> Jesus answered, "Thou couldest have no
power at all against me."
>> Except what?
>> Except it were given thee from above.
>> Ain't that book true? Yeah. Because we
read that in the Old Testament far
before Jesus came in the flesh and look
at him in the flesh telling Pilate what
it is. Go ahead.
>> Therefore, he that deliverth me unto
thee hath the greatest sin.
>> Yes, sir. He said the one that did this,
in other words, the scribes, the
Pharisees, they the ones in trouble.
Let's go to First Thessalonians the 5th
chapter.
He said they in trouble.
And then they threw us under the bus.
Let this blood be upon us, man. Our
children,
man. Lord, understand though.
That's cold blooded. You take your
family and throw them under the bus.
Was no such thing as a man
back then just standing up and dying for
what he did.
Except the thief on the cross
are the thieves.
First Thessalonians 5 and 22. What that
say, brother?
>> Abstain from all appearance of evil.
>> Wait a minute. From all what?
>> Appearance of evil.
>> That's why I say listen today
people think you smoking is what? Sin.
Lord ain't saying you can't smoke
because it it is not sin. However, when
you around somebody,
I don't care how bad you looking for
that feeling for that nicotine.
Lord said, uh-uh, don't do that. If they
offended,
he said cuz to them is evil. They don't
understand the book, but we do. You have
to abstain from that. And then there's
many other things we have to abstain
from
like them brothers that deal with and I
just got to say it multiple wife. You
can't do that cuz guess what everybody
else they see it they offended at that
and they ain't going to come to this
thing.
Then you giving God a bad name. He
looking at it. He said abstain from that
which is what?
>> All evil.
>> All evil. All evil. What else?
and the very God of peace sanctify you
holy.
>> Yeah, that's that's it.
>> Because he told us abstain from all
evil, right?
>> Yes.
>> Now, let's go to uh first Timothy. I
want to read this in first Timothy the
first chapter. No, the second chapter
cuz we say, "Hey, we ain't got to we
ain't supposed to pray for the uh the
leaders. They wicked."
Lord said, "Seek the seek the city. seek
for and when you're in a city, seek the
peace thereof.
Then he told you to pray for them.
Let's see in Paul's time what he said.
1 Timothy 2 and verse one.
I know Jesus said he wasn't going to
pray for
certain people and stuff like that, but
I ain't Jesus. I'm reading what he said
after.
Then you know what to pray for when you
do pray for him. Let's read two in one.
Brother two and one. 1 Timothy 2 and1.
Go ahead.
>> I exhort thee therefore that first of
all
>> Yes, sir.
>> supplications, prayers, intercessions,
and giving of thanks be made for all
men.
>> How many people?
>> All men.
>> For who? Go ahead.
>> For kings and for all that are in
authority.
>> Yes, sir. that we may lead a quiet and
peaceable life in all godliness and
honesty.
>> For it's for our peace, ain't it? Read.
>> For this is good and acceptable in the
sight of God our savior.
>> I did that when Well, no, I can't say
that cuz I don't want to cause uproar.
Go ahead and read.
>> Who will have all men to be saved and to
come unto the knowledge of the truth.
>> So that's what you really praying for.
You open these people minds. be open up
to the truth. Let them look at us as an
example.
>> Right?
>> Then you praying that they don't start
these these this drama. You praying that
the Lord cover you during that time
because the great tribulation is not
far. It's not far at all. Let's go to uh
Hebrews the 12th chapter.
Hebrews 12, read verse one. Just one
verse.
Hebrews 12 and verse one.
This is why he said abstain from all
evil and then pray for all that are in
authority.
I got three more spots
12 and one. Go ahead.
>> Wherefore saying we also are compassed
about with such with so great a cloud of
witnesses.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Let us lay aside every weight and the
sin which doth so easily beset us. He
said, "Listen, you got a cloud of
witnesses, people watching you. So, you
got to be careful." He said, "Right, go
ahead.
>> And let us run with patience the race
that is set before us."
>> He said, "You got to have patience."
And it hurt when we going through it. I
know how it hurts, but you still got to
be patient. The Lord always bring you
what? He bring you through it. What
else? That it
>> was in uh one
>> one. So, now let's go to Psalm 104.
Psalm 104. And then we just going to
look at our
children that's out there today.
Two spots for them.
We'll look at them children.
Psalm 104 and verse one. What did it
say?
>> Bless the Lord, oh my soul.
>> Yes sir. Oh Lord my God, thou art very
great.
>> Yes sir. What else?
>> Thou art clothed with honor and majesty.
>> Yes indeed. Skip down to verse five and
read that.
>> Who laid the foundations of the earth
that it should not be removed forever.
>> How long? Forever. So this earth going
to stand. Read.
>> Thou covers it.
>> No. Verse 10. I'm sorry.
>> He sendeth the springs into the valleys
which run among the hills.
>> What? Skip down to verse. No. Read uh
want to make sure verse 11. Read that 11
verse. Then we go.
>> They give drink to every beast of the
field. Yes. The wild asses quench their
thirst.
>> The Lord said, "I'm feeding everybody."
Skip down to verse 14.
>> He causes the grass to grow for the
cattle.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And herb for the service of man.
>> For the service.
>> That he may bring forth food out of the
earth.
>> So we can eat and drink. Oh.
>> And wine that maketh glad the heart of
man. He said, "I even give you some
wine, even some whiskey.
>> You just got to do it in moderation. The
Lord give us things to enjoy this in our
time, but you got to be wise when you do
it." Go ahead and read.
>> And oil to make his face to shine.
>> Uhhuh. We talking about that grease.
If you got Vaseline, that same thing,
that oil, I know we used to use that
when we was growing up. My mom put it on
our face and greasing our head
>> make you to shine. Go ahead and read
>> and bridge which strengthenth man's
heart.
>> You got the protein and all the things
that you have vegetables
to nourish your body. Right. Let's go to
Isaiah the fifth chapter 51st chapter.
Isaiah chapter 51
and we're going to read 19 and 20.
One more after this and it's going to be
in Isaiah.
two spots where our children when we
look at them.
We make sure that they not doing this.
And this right here, bring back
memories.
Start at verse 19. 51. Oh. Oh yeah. 51.
Isaiah
chapter 51 and verse. Start at verse 19
again. Brother,
>> these two things are come unto thee. Who
shall be sorry for thee?
>> Who shall be sorry for thee? Go ahead.
>> Desolation and destruction and the
famine and the sword. By whom shall I
comfort thee?
>> Now, if somebody was to get killed, man,
they they let your body lay there. But
if it was an animal, they get it up out
the streets quick.
>> Thy sons have faith.
>> They'll call Peter on you.
You mistreat an animal, cat or a dog,
got more love and value above you.
>> And these animals were created for us.
So why the Lord allowed that to happen?
Because he got all this knowledge in
this book. And if we fall is because we
don't have it. Go ahead and read 20.
>> Thy sons have figned.
>> They wait. Your sons did what?
>> Fain.
>> They gave up. What' they do?
They lie at the head of all the streets.
>> Wait a minute. And we in the corners
and that's everywhere I look. If you
over in England, you on the corners. I
saw it with my own eyes. And I know it's
true cuz I used to be on the corner
in the streets.
So I know that this is true. Who could
have called this other than God?
What they fulfilled with brother? Go
ahead. as a wild bull in that.
>> Yep.
>> They are full of the fury of the Lord.
>> Uhhuh. Because the Lord pulled that
drama out on them. Go ahead.
>> They rebuke of thy God.
>> Yes indeed. Let's go to the 42nd
chapter. Isaiah chapter 42. So you got
them in the streets and then when the
Lord either kill them or get them locked
up, where do they end up at?
Sometimes they learn better behavior in
this spot,
but they pick up the wrong religion.
This our last spot.
They end up picking up what?
Islam.
Then you got the Christianity.
There's not the true Christianity in
there just as well.
Then we starting to sprinkle in there
just a little bit to where the truth is
being taught.
So the Lord know we want to make sure
that we get a fair shake.
42 and verse 18. What that say, bro?
Isaiah 42:18. What it say?
>> Hear ye deaf and look ye blind that you
may see.
>> Wait a minute. If you blind, you ain't
going to be able to see. What he talking
about spiritually? and you deaf, you
can't hear it because it's all about you
and your desires. Go ahead.
>> Who is blind but my servant
>> or
>> or deaf as my messenger that I have
sent.
>> Who is what? Go ahead.
>> Who is blind is he that is perfect.
>> Wait a minute. The one that's blind is
the one that's perfect. You can't tell
them nothing.
I got this.
I'm the one. I know what God saying.
They tell you, "Listen, the Holy Ghost
gonna save me. I'm covered in grace."
How?
We don't want to hear nothing that's
hard for people. That means the Lord got
to use that belt that's in his hand that
we read earlier. Who the nations?
They'll put you down.
>> Then when they killing you in the
streets, everybody want to march. Nobody
still has picked up the book.
And that's why we got to go out and do
what? Evangelize.
So that we can spread that word. Let
them know 8145.
If you in Pennsylvania, go to this spot.
If you're in DC, go to this one. If
you're in the Bay Area, go to that one.
Baton Rouge, this one. Chicago,
Riverdale.
Wherever we are, the Lord got you a
location.
So nobody have no excuse. What he say,
brother? Go ahead. and blind as the
Lord's servant
>> as the Lord's servant you are. He sent
you his messenger. Meaning who you
supposed to go to? If all Israel got the
message and we all knowledgeable, who do
you supposed to go to? The nations.
Deuteronomy the fourth chapter told us
that.
He said the nations going to look and
say this is wise and understanding
people.
But we did what? Strengthen the hand of
the evil. We taught them the wicked the
wicked the wicked ways. Why? We left our
God and said what you serving is good.
They was like, "Oh, so serving a rock is
what it's supposed to be." Yeah.
Make sure you get us the music, the
food. We don't care about no rituals.
Just bring on that liquor, the women,
the men. We good with that. Go ahead and
read. Rob know that's true. He laughed
at it. Go ahead, brother.
>> Read 2020.
>> Okay.
>> Seeing many things, but thou observest
not.
>> Wait, you see a lot of stuff. There's so
much knowledge out here. He said, but
you see is not.
He told us that that many was going to
run to and fro. Knowledge going to be
increased. He didn't say all good
knowledge.
That's why you see people waking up,
they still hitting the head on the wall.
You like
Brothers and sisters say, "I just joined
this thing." And I'm like, "No, that
ain't the spot." But they just woke up.
Pretty soon they'll come across this.
But read though, brother. What else?
>> Opening your ears, but he heareth not.
>> Come on over there, man. Get on out
there with that Christian religion. Go
ahead.
>> The Lord is well pleased for his
righteousness sake.
>> Go ahead.
>> He will magnify the law and make it
honorable.
>> But this is a people robbed and spoiled.
>> Wait a minute. They robbed many. You got
taken when Nebuchadnezzar came over
there and got all your stuff. You ain't
had it since other than when Cyrus gave
it to you. 70 AD, we was taken out
completely.
And don't many people know where we are?
Some of them rulers do.
Over in Russia, they was talking about
it and they revealed some things. If you
watch this, you'll see them.
They'll show who Israel was. Old
paintings, pictures, sculpture
to make people mad. Go ahead and read,
brother.
>> There are all of them snaring in holes.
>> Wait a minute. They snaring in holes.
What else?
>> And they are hidden prison houses.
>> Wait, so ain't we in the prisons? Yes.
You on the street corners and you in the
prisons? Where else can they find you?
Go ahead. They are a prey and none
delivereth.
>> Wait. They are prey and nobody will
deliver them. Go ahead.
>> For a spoil and none saith, restore.
>> And nobody say restore. Go ahead.
>> Who among you will give ear to this?
>> Yep.
>> Who will hearken and hear for the time
to come?
>> For the time to come. Cuz guess what? It
got some drama coming. Go ahead.
>> Who gave Jacob for a spoil?
>> Uhhuh.
>> And Israel to robbers.
>> Who did this? Go ahead. did not the
Lord, he against whom we have sinned.
>> So why we keep talking about what the
white man did and what the habit did,
they didn't do nothing but what God told
them to do.
>> So you got brothers that do hold this
book and don't know what they talking
about cuz we didn't read cover to cover
what this thing was saying at so they
eyes ain't even on really
till the Lord hit them with this. Oh,
take the scales off and they start
seeing it. Go ahead and read though.
>> For they would not walk in his ways,
neither were they obedient unto his law.
Therefore, he has poured upon the poured
upon him the fury of his anger.
>> Yes indeed, brother go ahead.
>> And the strength of battle, and it has
set him on fire round about.
>> He said it's like you on fire on all
sides, east, west, south, and north. He
got the head on fire. You can't even put
it out. Go ahead.
>> Yet he knew not and it burned it.
>> Yes.
>> Yet he laid it not to heart.
>> And you ain't even say, "Why am I going
through this?"
And then we say, "Look, this right here,
the white man gave us this Bible. He
when we got off the slave ship, he gave
us his religion." I'm saying, "Hold on,
the gentile in here, too, and he getting
his destruction coming.
And if they listen, let's just say they
wrote this.
Wouldn't you take home side of me out?
Would you take that out?
>> Would you take out? If you eat unclean
things, the Lord ain't going to come
back and destroy. They do all these
things. So when they take that out, if
they really wanted you to know
or didn't want you to know this,
>> right?
I ain't going to put nothing in the book
that's going to condemn me. If I'm
writing in a story don't look good.
That's foolishness. So when the Lord say
the obey the powers that be. He said I
set them up and it's for your benefit
till I get back. Pray for these. Pray
for one another. Walk in righteousness
always. if you don't. He said, "I got
somebody in place for you and our
brothers and sisters that's running out
there doing this te what is it? Teenage
uh takeover.
We got to get We got to get irrit
St. Louis will probably do it.
You just don't want them to come across
you while you getting off work, man."
And they jumping on your car, pushing
it. They feel in the streets gonna look
at it y'all.
Until the National Guard come in and
kill a lot of them, they won't be happy.
And their parents is allowing them to do
it.
Till then, somebody come stop them. We
going to die, y'all. We going to
continue to die.
So now we understand what the powers
that be was about. These authorities is
over us. make sure we obey them or else
we got somebody greater to answer to. I
hope y'all got something from it and I
thank you for your time.
We got you
announcements.